GINA KENNEDY: Balance poses can be very challenging and a little scary when they're upside down.
Through the use of blocks, it can make the fear go right out of it, or at least we hope so.
So, Faith is going to help me demonstrate Bakasana, or the crane balance.
So, we're just going to have her come over to her hands and curl her toes under.
Yeah, she's going to take her knees wide and place her hands in between her knees and spread her fingers nice and wide; now, notice how she bent her elbows and pull them to the insides of her knees.
Good.
She's going to pull her belly in and lift her tailbone up and bring her knees to her upper arm bones.
She's going to transfer her weight a little bit forward, and just lean her head right on that block, and what this does is takes the fear out of falling forward.
Good.
Then also, we're going to take a block and place it under her feet.
There.
So, basically, she has more points to lean on and she does not have to worry about falling over.
Good.
I'm going to release the block and slowly come back down.
So, if that's still even a little scary for you, you might try having a pillow in front and a pillow under your tail so you're not worried about falling over.
Because the key to arm balance poses is to lose your fear.